Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
Emory University
Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
O'Grady, Desmond, 1935-
Manuscript Collection No. 911
39 linear ft. (78 boxes) and 12 oversized papers (OP)
Personal and literary papers of Irish poet and translator, Desmond O'Grady from 1953-2001.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 2002.
Restrictions on access
Special restrictions apply: Letters by Seamus Heaney are closed to researchers.
Collection stored off-site. Researchers must contact MARBL in advance to access this collection.
Biographical Note
Desmond O'Grady was born in 1935 in Limerick, Ireland. He holds an M.A. and Ph.D from Harvard University. He is a charter member of Aosdana and served as the Irish representative to Congress of the Community of European Writers in 1962 and 1965. His published works include volumes of poetry, Chords and Orchestrations, Reilly, The Dark Edge of Europe, The Dying Gaul, Hellas, Separations, Stations, Sing Me Creation, His Skaldcrane's Nest, The Wandering Celt, Alexandrian Notebook, and Tipperary; and translations Off Licence, The Gododdin, A Limerick Rake, Grecian Glances, The Seven Arab Odes, Ten Modern Arab Poets, and Trawling Tradition. O'Grady is the father of three children, Deirdre Anne Maria, Leonard John Jules, and Gisele Eleanor Anne.
Scope and Content Note
The Desmond O'Grady papers include literary and personal papers of the poet and translator, Desmond O'Grady from 1953-2001. The bulk of the collection consists of drafts of O'Grady's own writings, including poems from Chords and Orchestrations, Reilly, The Dark Edge of Europe, The Dying Gaul, Hellas, Separations, Stations, Sing Me Creation, His Skaldcrane's Nest, The Wandering Celt, Alexandrian Notebook, and Tipperary and translations from Off Licence, The Gododdin, A Limerick Rake, Grecian Glances, The Seven Arab Odes, Ten Modern Arab Poets, and Trawling Tradition. Also present are extensive files of personal and literary correspondence including letters from Samuel Beckett, Seamus Heaney, Derek Mahon, James Simmons, and Richard Ellmann. The collection also includes writings by others, personal files (including diaries and other personal items), collected printed material either by or about Desmond O'Grady, photographs, and sound recordings.
Arrangement Note
Organized into six series: (1) Correspondence, (2) Writings by Desmond O'Grady, (3) Writings of others, (4) Personal files, (5) Printed material, and (6) Audio-visual materials.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Astley, Neil.; Banville, John.; Beckett, Samuel, 1906-1989.; Bolger, Dermot, 1959-; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-; Dorgan, Theo.; Egan, Desmond.; Ellmann, Richard, 1918-; Fallon, Peter, 1951-; Hartnett, Michael, 1941-; Heaney, Seamus, 1939-; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998.; Johnston, Dillon.; Kennelly, Brendan.; Kiely, Benedict.; Kinsella, Thomas.; Mahon, Derek, 1941-; MacIntyre, Tom.; Muldoon, Paul.; Ni Chuuilleanain, Eilean.; O'Keeffe, Timothy.; Ormsby, Frank, 1947-; Simmons, James, 1933-; Simms, Jacqueline, 1940-
Topical Terms
English literature--Irish authors--20th century.; Irish poetry--20th century.; Poets, Irish--20th century.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Poems.; Translations.
Occupation
Poet.
Finding Aid Note
A selected index of prominent correspondents is available.
Related Materials in This Repository
Peter Fallon/Gallery Press collection.
Description of Series
- Correspondence, 1953-2001, Series 1; Boxes 1 - 27
  Scope and Content Note
  The correspondence series in the Desmond O'Grady papers includes letters dating from 1953-2001, with the largest portion from the 1980's and 1990's. Literary correspondents include Samuel Beckett, Seamus Heaney, Derek Mahon, Peter Fallon, Edward Said, and Richard Ellmann. There is a small amount of restricted correspondence from Seamus and Marie Heaney.
  Arrangement Note
  Arranged in chronological order with restricted correspondence filed at the end.
  Finding Aid Note
  A selected index of prominent correspondents is available.
  Restrictions on access
  Special restrictions apply: Letters by Seamus Heaney are closed to researchers.
  - 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1974 January-May (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1974 June-September (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1974 October-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1975 January-June (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1975 July-December (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1976 January-August (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1976 September-December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1977 January-May (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1977 June-August (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1977 September-October (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1977 November-December (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1978 January-February (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1978 March-April (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1978 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1978 June-July (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1978 August-October (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1978 November-December (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1979 January-April (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1979 May-July (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1979 August-October (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1979 November-December (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1980 January-March (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1980 April-June (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1980 July-December (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1982 January-June (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1982 July-August (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1982 September (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1982 November-December (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1983 January-February (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1983 March-June (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1983 July-August (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1983 September-December (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1984 January-March (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1984 April-July (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1984 August-September (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1984 October-December (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1985 January-March (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1985 April-June (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1985 July-August (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1985 September-December (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1987 January-June (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1987 July-September (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1987 October-December (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1988 January-May (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1988 June-December (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1989 January-April (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1989 May-August (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1989 September-December (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1990 January-March (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1990 April-August (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1990 September-December (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1991 January-June (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1991 July-December (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1992 January-August (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1992 September-December (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1993 January-June (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1993 July-September (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1993 October-December (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1994 January-March (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1994 April-June (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1994 July-September (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1994 October-December (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1995 January-March (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1995 April-June (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1995 July-September (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1995 October-December (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1996 January-May (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1996 June-July (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1996 August-October (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1996 November-December (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1997 January-March (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 1997 April (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1997 May-August (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 1997 September-October (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 1997 November-December (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 1998 January-July (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1998 August-December (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1999 January-April (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1999 May-June (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1999 July-September (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1999 October-December (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 2000 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 2001 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Notebook with drafts of letters, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Undated indexed correspondents (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, undated from indexed correspondents (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards, 1959-1977 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Greeting cards, 1980-1982 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Greeting cards, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, 1985-1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Greeting cards, 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Greeting cards, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, 1999-2000 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1974-1989 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1990-1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, 1995-2001 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Restricted correspondence
  - Seamus Heaney, 1990-2000 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Writings by Desmond O'Grady, 1956-2002, Series 2; Boxes 28 - 51
  The writings by Desmond O'Grady found in this series include collected and uncollected poems, prose, translations by O'Grady, translations of O'Grady, and notebooks. In Subseries 2.1a individual poems are filed alphabetically within each collection; the collections are arranged chronologically by publication date. Included in Subseries 2.1b are several uncollected poems, arranged alphabetically. When multiple poems appear on a single manuscript page, cross references have been provided. O'Grady's prose is located in Subseries 2.2 and is arranged alphabetically and divided under the headings, Essays, Articles, and Reviews, Short Stories and Novels, and Drama. Subseries 2.3 contains several of O'Grady's drafts of translations. Individual translations are filed alphabetically by author within each collection; the collections are arranged chronologically by publication date. Subseries 2.4 contains Italian translations of O'Grady's work and arranged alphabetically by title.
  Subseries 2.5 contains several of O'Grady's manuscript notebooks. These notebooks contain manuscript drafts of poems from Tipperary, as well as drafts of translations, and essays on literature. Additional manuscripts of O'Grady's work may also be found in the diaries located in Subseries 4.1, Personal and family items.
  Organized into five subseries: (2.1) Poems, (2.2) Prose, (2.3) Translations by O'Grady, (2.4) Translations of O'Grady, and (2.5) Notebooks.
  - Poems, 1956-2002, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 28 - 38
    Organized into two groups: (2.1a) Collected poems and (2.1b) Uncollected poems.
    - Collected poems, 1956-2002, Subseries 2.1a; Boxes 28 - 35: folder 6
      - Chords and Orchestrations (1956)
      - "Seven Songs," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Reilly (1961)
      - "Departure," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - "Epiphany," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - "From Rome's Capitol Hill," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - "Island," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - "My Last Conversation with Denis Devlin," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - "The Poet in Old Age Fishing at Evening," MS (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - "Roman Elegy I," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - "Roman Elegy II," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "The World's Lovemonger," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - The Dying Gaul (1968)
      - The Dying Gual, MS (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - The Dark Edge of Europe (1969)
      - "The Colossus of Maroussi," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - "Girl and Widow on a Sea Park Bench," TS [variant title: "Girl and Widow"] (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - "Nikos Gatsos," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - "Patrick Kavanagh," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - "The Seaman's Flower in the Garden," TS [variant title: "The Seaman's Flower"] (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Hellas (1971)
      - Hellas, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Hellas, proofs w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Separations (1973)
      - "Compatriots," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Friends"] (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - "Envoi," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - "Ezra Pound in Venice," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - "Gisele Unwell," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - "Roman Elegy III," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - "Summer Nights," TS (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Stations (1976)
      - "Bettina's Song," TS (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - "Betting," TS (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - "Desert Crow," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - "Harvest," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - "Sahara," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - A Limerick Rake (1978)
      - "The Poet and His Dog," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - "The Poet's Request," TS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, A Limerick Rake, "The Poet and His Dog"] (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - His Skaldcrane's Nest (1979)
      - "Farewell," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - "Fathers and Sons," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - "My Country," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Ireland"] (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - "Pain," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - "Robert Lowell," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - "Roman Autumn," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - "Unicorn," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 38)
      - Preliminary table of contents, TS and MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - The Headgear of the Tribe (1979)
      - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 40)
      - These Fields in Springtime (1984)
      - These Fields in Springtime, TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 41)
      - Notes (Box 28, Folder 42)
      - The Wandering Celt (1984)
      - "The Amber Route," TS (Box 28, Folder 43)
      - "At Home in Rome," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 44)
      - "Arabs," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The First Qasida"] (Box 28, Folder 45)
      - "The Book of Job," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - "Caesar on Vercingetorix," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 47)
      - "The Camps," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Camps in General"] (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - "Catullus on Caesar," MS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - "Celts in Britain," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 50)
      - "Christ's Crucifixion," TS w/ corrections (Box 28, Folder 51)
      - "Cicero's Old Age," TS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, Tipperary, "Gisele at Eighty, TS] (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "Cities," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "Crucifixion," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Crucifixion Sura"] (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - "Cycladic Sura," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - "Divitiacus Before the Roman Senate 60 B.C.," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - "Egyptians," MS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Black Land" and "The Nile"] (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - "The Elder Seneca on Ovid," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Seneca the Elder on Ovid in Rome"] (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - "Gaius Cilnius Maecenas," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Gaius Maecenas"] (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - "Gallo-Romans," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Gallo-Roman Sura"] (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - "The Gate to the Garden," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "The Gate to the Field," "XV," "Frontier Guard," and "The Gatekeeper"] (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - "The Great Horse Fair," TS (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - "Greek Sura," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - "Harper," TS (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - "Hebrews," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Semites"] (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - "Hieroglyphics," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - "Horse," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - "Hugh O'Neill in Rome," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - "Joseph and Potiphar's Wife," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - "Joseph Brodsky," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - "La Dolce Vita," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - "Language," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - "Letter from a Roman Celt Serving in Judea," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - "Livy," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - "Love Song," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - "Mary Magdalene," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - "Moses," MS w/ corrections [See Subseries 2.1, Poetry, The Wandering Celt, "Hebrews" and "Moses on the Mount"] (Box -, -)
      - "Moses on the Mount," MS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, The Wandering Celt, "Hebrews," MS"] (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - "The Nile," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - "The Normans in Ireland," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "The Normans of Limerick," and "The Barrington Normans of Limerick"] (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - "Odysseus in the Underworld," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - "Ovid from Exile," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - "Palm Print," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - "Papyrus," MS (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - "The People of Maikop Plain," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - "Petrarch," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - "Petrarch's Laura," MS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, The Wandering Celt, "Petrarch," TS] (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - "Pillow Talk," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Belfast Pillow Talk" and "Belfast Bedroom"] (Box 29, Folder 36)
      - "Pindar on Simonides," TS (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - "Qasida," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 38)
      - "Relics," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Ruins"] (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - "Return to Rome," TS and MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Return"] (Box 29, Folder 40)
      - "Roman Art," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Roman Art Sura"] (Box 29, Folder 41)
      - "Script," MS [See Subseries 2.1, Poetry, The Wandering Celt, "Papyrus"] (Box -, -)
      - "Sculptor," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Herzl Emanuel: Sculptor"] (Box 29, Folder 42)
      - "Simonides of Ceos," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 43)
      - "The Song of Songs," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - "Sound," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - "Standing Stone," TS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 46)
      - "10 Piazza Campitelli," MS w/ corrections (Box 29, Folder 47)
      - "Thoughts of Virgil," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Virgil" and "Sketches of Virgil"] (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - "3 Piazza Mattei," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - "Tiberius," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - "Trastevere House," MS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - "Troy to Rome," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Greeks and Trojans"] (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - "Two Brothers," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Brothers"] (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - "Vercingetorix," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - "Vikings," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The One Spring the Viking..."] [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, A Limerick Rake, "The Poet's Request"] (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - "A Walk in Rome," TS and MS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Morning Walk" and "Roman Walk"] (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - "The Wandering Celt," TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - "The Women," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Women in Particular"] (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - "Writing Out of Doors," TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - The Wandering Celt, TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - The Wandering Celt, TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - A lexandrian Notebook (1989)
      - "Alexandria," MS (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - "Alexandrian Spring," TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - "Alix of Alexandria," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - "The Arab Quarter," MS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - "The Beach at Montazah," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - "The Capri Hotel," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - "Cavafy in Alexandria," MS and TS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, Alexandrian Notebook, "Alexandria," MS] (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - "Child Flies Kite," TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - "Cockroach," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - "Evensong," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - "Fellaheen in Town," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - "Hotel Union," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - "In an Alexandrian Garden," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - "Lack," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - "The Metropole Hotel," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - "Moustaches," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - "My Day for Pastroudis," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "My Day for the Cecil"] (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - "Neighbour," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - "On Board Ship," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - "Pastroudis Revisited," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - "Stranger," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - "Taverna Tropicana," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - "Uum Kalthoum," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Nightingale of the Nile"] (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Alexandrian Notebook, MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: Alexandria Notebook and Alexandrian Attitudes] (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Book jacket material, MS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Preliminary table of contents, MS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Tipperary (1991)
      - "Aging Satyr," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Old Satyr"] (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - "Aging Siren," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - "Asphodels," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Viola" and "You"] (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - "Birds of a Feather," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Herons"] (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - "Breakup," TS (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - "Brothers," MS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - "Captain Linardos Malamantegna," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Captain Leonardos"] (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - "Child at Play," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - "Children," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - "Circus," TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Town Circus," "Local Circus," "Clown with Trumpet," and "Daffey's Circus"] (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - "Crows of the Imagination," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - "A Drowned Fisherman Aged 21," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Requiem for a Drowned Fisherman"] (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - "Exile from Exile," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Wayfarer"] (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - "Exordium," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Quest"] (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - "Farmer," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 24)